Nicolas Nucifora

■ nuciforanicolas@gmail.com

+39 388-8735636

C

in <u>Nicolas Nucifora</u>

Portfolio

Video Game Programmer with a solid background in computer science and a strong passion for game development. My expertise covers AI programming and gameplay systems development. I work daily with the Unreal Engine and the C++ programming language.

Experience

System & AI Programmer - Stormind Games S.R.L

March 2023-Present

- Developed an intelligent behavior for the main enemy of the video game A Quiet Place: the road ahead through the use of the Unreal Engine AI development framework, specifically the Behavior Tree system, Environment Query system and navigation system were used
- Created a system that can dynamically change the AI difficulty level, by modifying certain parameters, based on the player's performance
- Developed a microphone noise detection system based on the default Unreal Engine system and modified its C++ code to fix some bugs and complete missing parts to make it work on all consoles
- Created an Hint system, to help player to find objectives and point of interest easily.
- Collaborated with a multidisciplinary team of designers, artists, and sound engineers to ensure seamless integration of AI systems and game mechanics, maintaining a cohesive game experience.

Generalist Game Programmer - Red Raion S.R.L

2022-2023

- Developed a VR serious game for PC and Meta Quest to gameify lower limb rehabilitation
- Demonstrated ability to manage and complete video game development as a sole developer, going through every stage of development
- Demonstrated ability to communicate and collaborate with external partners to identify and implement project requirements

Shipped games

A Quiet Place: the road ahead (PS5, Xbox Series X/S, PC) - Stormind Games / Saber Interactive

Batora: Lost Haven (PS4, PS5, Xbox One, Xbox Series X/S, PC, Nintendo Switch) - Stormind Games

Smart Rehab (PC) - Red Raion S.R.L

Education

University of Catania

2017-2021

- Bachelor of Science, Computer Science
- Vote: 110/110
- Thesis: Finite State Machine: artificial Intelligence in video games
- Highlight courses: Video Game development (C#, Unity3D), Programming I II (C++, sorting algorithms, data structures), Software Engineering (Java, Design patterns), Operative System, DataBase, Computer Network, Math, Internet Security

Skills

Unreal Engine 5

C++, Blueprint Visual scripting

Behavior tree, Navigation System, Environment Query System (EQS)

Languages

Italian: native

English: intermediate